Guide to the Bostwick Company Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Bostwick Company records
1819-1856
MS 625
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(1 box)
The records consist of correspondence from the business records of William Bostwick (1796-1863), merchant of Augusta, Georgia, and New Haven, Connecticut, who dealt primarily in cotton. While most of the letters are on business, there are personal letters (1854, 1856) from Benjamin Silliman, Noah Porter, James Browning Miles, and Willis Strong Colton. The records also include sixty-two account books.
Bostwick Company
Conditions Governing Access
The entire collection is available on microfilm. Patrons must use FILM HM 134 instead of the originals.
Existence and Location of Copies
Entire collection also available on microfilm (9,891 frames on 12 reels, 35mm.) from Scholarly Resources, Inc., Wilmington, Delaware.
Arrangement
Records arranged alphabetically by company.
Scope and Contents
The Bostwick Company Records, 1819-1856, consist of the business records of William Bostwick (1796-1863), merchant of Augusta, Georgia, and New Haven, Connecticut, including records of firms with which he was associated and their antecedents. The firms represented are: Edward Campfield & Co.; John Burton, Burton & Bostwick; Banks & Baird; and Bostwick & Baird, the last-named becoming the firm of William Bostwick in 1832. All of these firms were in Augusta, Georgia, and were primarily engaged in the cotton business.
The records are arranged alphabetically by title and run nearly continuously from 1819 to 1856 with the records of succeeding companies often being simply continued in old record books. An indication has been given under each of the entries in the register as to which companies are included with that particular set of records.
NOTE: In 1982, the entire collection was filmed (HM Film 134). The volumes were discarded after filming, but the correspondence, including the letters which were in box 5 folder 50, has been kept and refoldered. They are described on the following page.
Business; Cotton trade -- Georgia; Cotton -- Commerce; Southern States; Account books; Bostwick, William, 1796-; Burton, John; Colton, Willis Strong; Miles, James Browning, 1822-1875; Porter, Noah, 1811-1892; Silliman, Benjamin, 1779-1864; Banks & Baird; Bostwick & Baird; Bostwick Company; Burton & Bostwick; Edward Campfield & Co
- Correspondence
  - 1840-1844 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1845-1846 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1847-1848, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Benjamin Silliman, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Noah Porter, James Browning Miles, Willis Strong Colton: invitations, 1854, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Microfilm Inventory
  - Account book (1v.), 1827 May - 1837 September (Reel 1)
    General note
    (Banks & Baird, William Bostwick)
  - Bill book (1v.), 1819 February - 1856 May (Reel 1)
  - Bill of lading books (3v.), 1826-1842
    (Edward Campfield & Co., Burton & Bostwick, Bostwick & Baird, William Bostwick)
    - v.1: 1826 Jun - 1840 Oct (Reel 1)
    - v.2: 1830 Mar - 1836 Nov (Reel 1)
    - v.3: 1836 Oct - 1842 Nov (Reel 1)
  - Book of charges on goods (1v.), 1822 November - 1826 June (Reel 1)
    (John Burton)
  - Cash books (3v.), 1830-1846
    (Bostwick & Baird, William Bostwick)
    - v.1: 1830 Jun - 1833 May (Reel 1)
    - v.2: 1833 May - 1838 Jun (Reel 1)
    - v.3: 1838 Jan - 1846 Apr (Reel 1)
  - Cash sales (3v.), 1825-1843
    (John Burton, Burton & Bostwick, Bostwick & Baird, William Bostwick)
    - v.1: 1825 May - 1835 Jan (Reel 1)
    - v.2: 1835 Jan - 1840 Jan (Reel 1)
    - v.3: 1840 Jan - 1843 May (Reel 1)
  - Cotton books
    - (2v.), 1822-1826 (Box 2)
    - (1v.), 1826 January - 1829 February (Box 2)
    - (1v.), 1827 October - 1836 June (Box 3)
  - Day books
    - (1v), 1823 May - 1829 June (Box 3)
    - (10v.), 1830 January - 1842 May (Box 3)
      - v.A: 1830 Jun - Dec (Box 3)
      - v.B: 1831 Jan - Sep (Box 3)
      - v.C: 1831 Oct - 1832 Jul (Box 4)
      - v.D: 1832 Aug - 1833 Jul (Box 4)
      - v.E: 1833 Aug - 1834 Nov (Box 4)
      - v.F: 1834 Nov - 1836 Feb (Box 5)
      - v.G: 1836 Feb - 1837 Jul (Box 5)
        Shelved separately
      - v.H: 1837 Jul - 1838 Oct (Box 5)
      - v.I: 1838 Oct - 1840 Jan (Box 6)
      - v.K: 1840 Jan - 1842 May (Box 6)
  - Expense account (1v.), 1830 June - 1843 June (Box 6)
    Also contains memorandums 1828 Oct - 1830 Mar (William Bostwick)
  - Inventory of stock (2v.), 1832-1843
    (William Bostwick)
    - v.1: 1832 May - 1836 Jun (Box 6)
    - v.2: 1837 Jun - 1843 Jun (Box 6)
  - Journals
    - (1v.), 1826 June - 1830 May (Box 6)
    - (2v.), 1829-1836 (Box 7)
  - Ledgers
    - (1v.), 1825 September - 1828 October (Box 8)
    - (1v.), 1826 June - 1828 November (Box 8)
    - (3v.), 1829-1848 (Box 8)
  - Letter books (copies of letters sent)(4v.), 1826-1843
    - v.1: 1826 Jun - 1831 Jun (Box 10)
    - v.2: 1831 Jun - 1836 Mar (Box 10)
    - v.3: 1836 Apr - 1841 Feb (Box 10)
    - v.4: 1841 Mar - 1848 Feb (Box 11)
  - Memorandum books
    - (1v.), 1826 June - 1838 October (Box 11)
    - (10v.), 1830-1839 (Box 11)
    - (1v.), 1838 October - 1845 October (Box 11)
  - Notes and bills payable and receivable (4v.), 1826-1843
    (Burton & Bostwick, Bostwick. & Baird, William Bostwick)
    - v.1: 1826-1830 (Box 12)
    - v.2: 1829-1833 (Box 12)
    - v.3: 1833-1836 (Box 12)
    - v.4: 1836-1843 (Box 12)
  - Petty cash book (1v.), 1826 June - 1832 June (Box 12)
    (Edward Campfield & Co.)
  - Receipt book (1v.), 1827 May - 1835 December (Box 12)
    (Burton & Bostwick, Bostwick & Baird, William Bostwick)
  - Sales book (1v.), 1826 June - 1837 April (Box 12)
  - Misc. letters received by William Bostwick (Box 12)
    (ALS from Benjamin Silliman of 1854 Dec 29; printed invitations signed by Noah Porter and Willis Strong Colton, 1854-1856)